American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 28, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Dickson, Samuel, 1837-1915
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns changes in rules of administration. Refers to Secretaries, Librarian, Committees on Publication and Hall.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 28, 1898; 9x6; Rawle, William Brooke, 1843-1915
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns printed Catalogue of A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 29, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns report of Publications Committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 29, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lancaster County Historical Society (Pa.)
    Lanc[aster], Pa., A.L.S.: S. M. Sener, on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for copy of Mercer's paper on illuminated manuscripts of the Pennsylvania Germans.
  - Letter to T. B. [sic, Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 29, 1898; 10-1/2x8; School District of Philadelphia, Pa. Board of Public Education
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Asks about objects of local historic interest in A.P.S. library and Hall.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 30, 1898; 6-1/4x8; Dickson, Samuel, 1837-1915
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Sends changes in rules of administration.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 30, 1898; 7x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. Withdraws as Councillor because of deafness.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 30, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: F[rederick] W[ebb] Hodge 2p. Sends list of A.P.S. publications in its collection.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 1, 1898; 11x8-1/2; R. R. Bowker Company
    New York, Printed L. with MS. addition 1p. Concerns A.P.S. entries in American Catalogue.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 1, 1898; 8-1/2x5-3/4; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends report of publications Committee.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Dec. 1, 1898; 8x5; Fewkes, Jesse Walter, 1850-1930
    Kearn's Canyon, Ariz., A.L.S. 1p. Cannot send books. Refers to F.W. Putnam.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 1, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Smyth, Albert Henry, 1863-1907
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Asks about progress of his paper on Pericles. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 206-312.
  - Letter to George F[rederick] Barker, Dec. 1, 1898; 10-1/2x8; United States. Division of Forestry
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S.: Gifford Pinchot 1p., end. Asks for list of A.P.S. member and officers.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 1, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Library of Congress
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Herbert Friedenwald 2p. Note in Hays' hand pasted to 2d sheet Biblio. question about "Boston Independent Chronicle." Note gives extract from Ford's biblio. of Franklin, p.165.
  - Report on A.P.S. collections and renovation of Hall, Dec. 2, 1898; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] D.S.: Henry Pettit, Benj[amin] Smith Lyman, J[ames] Cheston Morris 5p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns disposition of collections and work done in North Room of Hall in Summer, 1897. Cf. Proceedings, v.37, pp.336, 337.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 2, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Ware, Lewis S. (Lewis Sharpe), 1851-1918
    [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Gives address. Refers to H.C. Baird.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], Dec. 3, 1898; 10-3/4x8; Garrett, Philip C. (Philip Cresson), 1834-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Meeting of Finance Committee.
  - Letter to Rudolph Buti, Baltimore, Dec. 5, 1898; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Copy. Committee on his paper on the "Book of the Dead" fragment cannot accept it but asks for a brief statement in its place.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 5, 1898; 10x8; Jones, Charles Edgeworth
    Augusta, Ga., A.L.S. 1p. Sending various publication of Confederate Survivors Association for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 5, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns bill from MacCalla.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 7, 1898; 10-1/2x8, 6-1/4x4-1/4; Dickson, Samuel, 1837-1915
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. of 1p. MS. note by Hays Concerns amendments. Magellanic premium. Hays' memorandum lists recipients of Magellanic premium.
  - Letter to George F[rederick] Barker, Dec. 7, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Harper & Brothers
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for copy of membership list.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 7, 1898; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew
    [London], A.L.S.; W[illiam] T[urner] Thiselton-Dyer 2p. Declines to exchange publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 7, 1898; 10-1/2x8; University of Pennsylvania. Library
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Morris Jastrow, Jr. 1p. Asks about acquisition of British governement publications. Refers to J.G. Rosengarten.
  - Letter to Ella Morison, Dec. 8, 1898; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Ware, Lewis S. (Lewis Sharpe), 1851-1918
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p., end., and add. Thanks for Proceedings.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 9, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Delaware Historical Society
    Wilmington, Del., L.S.: Henry C[lay] Conrad, Librarian 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to R[ussell] A[lexander] Alger, Secretary of War, Dec. 9, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Forwards A.P.S. request for documents. Encloses printed reply from War Department. With covering letter from Penrose to I.M. Hays, Dec. 17, 1898.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 9, 1898; 11x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington, D.C., Typed L.S. 1p. Will try to obtain requested documents for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 10, 1898; 11-1/4x8-1/2; Hopkins, A. D. (Andrew Delmar), 1857-1948
    Morgantown, W. Va., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns his work on Scolytids.
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Dec. 10, 1898; 10-1/4x8; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S.: Wm. A. Ingham, J. Cheston Morris, with additions in Morris' hand 1p. Lists nominations for offices.
  - Letter to Persifer [sic] Frazer, Dec. 12, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership list.
  - Letter to J[sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Dec. 13, 1898; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington [D.C.] Typed L.S.: David J[ayne] Hill 1p. Has forwarded publications to Dutch National Museum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Buti, Rudolph
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. Will prepare requested statement on fragment of the "Book of the dead."
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 14, 1898; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Instituto Físico-Geográfico Nacional de Costa Rica
    San José, A.L.S.: [Henri François] Pittier de Fabrega 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 14, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Minute Book for next meeting.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 14, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: F[rederick] W[ebb] Hodge 1p. Acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. publications.
  - Letter to [Robert Stewart] Culin, Dec. 16, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Saville, Marshall H. (Marshall Howard), 1867-1935
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns Culin's paper on Montezuma Tributeroll, and relationship of Phila. fragments to manuscripts in Berlin. Refers to E. Seler. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol.17, pp. 53-61.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 17, 1898; 9x6; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from M.H. Saville about his paper on Montezuma Tribute-roll. For enclosure, see Saville to Culin, Dec. 16, 1898. For pinted paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s. vol.17, pp. 53-61.
  - Letter to S. Raymond Roberts, Glenridge, N.J., Dec. 17, 1898; 3-1/4x5-1/4; Kegan Paul, Trench, Trübner & Co., Ltd.
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add., end.: Dr. Nolan Order for publication.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Dec. 19, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Collins, Varnum Lansing, 1870-1936
    Princeton, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks about published calendar of Lee manuscripts For printed calendar, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 38, pp. 114-131.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 19, 1898; 10-1/2x8; United States. Dept. of Agriculture
    Washington, Typed L.S.: W[illiam] P[arker] Cutter 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 20, 1898; 9-1/4x5-3/4; Hoffman, J. W.
    Orangeburg, S.C., A.L.S. 1p., end. by F. Prime Asks to be become member.
  - Letter to M. J. Hays [sic, Isaac Minis Hays], Dec. 20, 1898; 8x5; Pennypacker, Samuel W. (Samuel Whitaker), 1843-1916
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about number of Franklin imprints in A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to J. Minus Hayes [sic], Dec. 22, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Wootten, W. F.
    Reading, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Announces death of John E. Wootten.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 23, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p Concerns bill from MacCalla.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic], Dec. 24, 1898; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Leonard, James Biddle, 1845?-1900
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of membership list.
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Dec. 24, 1898; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Vaux, George
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. by Frazer Will serve as Clerk at elections.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Dec. 27, 1898; 8x5; Mitchell, James T. (James Tyndale), 1834-1915
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerns meeting of Committee on Historical Manuscripts.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 28, 1898; 8x5-1/2; Ely, Theo. N. (Theodore Newell), 1846-1916
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of membership list.
  - Letter to Frederick Prime, Dec. 28, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. with prime's disapproval of action proposed Asks Prime's approval of circular to be sent to nominees for office.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 28, 1898; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Library Committee meeting called.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Dec. 28, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: F[rederick] W[ebb] Hodge 1p. Enc. wanting Sends letter from Pittier de Fabrega.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 29, 1898; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Curator.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 29, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Trumbull, Annie Eliot, 1857-1949
    Hartford, Ct., A.L.S. 2p. Sending books from collection of father, J.H. Trumbull, for A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Cleemann, Richard A. (Richard Alsop), 1840-1912
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Secretary.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 8x5; Edmunds, George F. (George Franklin), 1828-1919
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Councillor.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Fisher, Sydney George, 1856-1927
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Accepts nomination as Secretary.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society; Phila.], Dec. 30, 1898; 6x5-1/4; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    L. in 3d person 1p. Accepts nomination as President.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 9x5-3/4; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Dec. 30, 1898; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 3p. Concerns paper on Lepidoptera. Refers to J.H. Comstock.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Councillor. Dislikes circular sent to nominees.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 7-1/2x5-1/2; Pinart, A. L. (Alphonse Louis), 1852-1911
    Paris, A.L.S. Asks to exchange his publications on American linguistics for Franz Boas papers printed in A.P.S. Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 9-1/2x6; Reade manufacturing company
    New York, Typed L.S.: W. J. Reade 1p., end. Orders copy of Proceedings, no.157.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Dec. 30, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 8x5; Trumbull, H. Clay (Henry Clay), 1830-1903
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Dec. 30, 1898; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Société de statistique de Paris
    Paris, A.L.S.: [Emile] Yvernès 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 10-1/2x8; Wistar, Isaac J. (Isaac Jones), 1827-1905
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Accepts nomination as Vice President.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 30, 1898; 7x4-1/2; Wurts, Charles Stewart, 1830-1907
    Phila., L. 1p. Accepts nomination as Councillor.
  - Invitation to memorial meeting for Harrison Allen and George H[enry] Horn, Dec. 31, 1898; 7x5-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    on Printed D. filled in in MS. 1p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1898; 8x5-1/4; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1898; 11x8-1/2; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Pinehurst, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Vice President.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1898; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1898; 8x5-1/2; Macfarlane, John Muirhead, 1855-1943
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. wanting Forwards inquiry from E.J. Nolan.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 31, 1898; 8x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
  - Preliminary Notes, 1898, 1900; 18x12-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Biographical sketches and memoranda chronologically arranged, for insertion in the Curator's Catalogue of Portraits, Busts, and Basreliefs in the Collection. Illustrated by photographs taken from the originals by Mr. Julius F. Sachse.. .Compiled by Henry Pettit, Curator; D. 1vol.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, 1898; 8x5; Jayne, Horace, 1859-1913
    [Phila.,] A.L.S. 1p. Accepts nomination as Treasurer.
  - Memorandum to the [American philosophical society;], 1898; 9-1/2x6-1/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim,]. A.D.S. 3p. Concerns text to accompany plates. Written on versos of proofs of plates.
  - Report of committee on Rudolph Buti's paper, to Persifor Frazer, 1898; 9x5-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    [Phila.,] Typed D.S.: H[ermann] V[olrath] Hilprecht, Sara Y[orke] Stevenson 3p. Refers to T. Williams.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, 1898; 8x5; Rhoads, Samuel N. (Samuel Nicholson), b. 1862
    [Pittsburgh,] A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Has not received manuscript of his paper on beavers. Sends bill for photographs. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, n.s., vol. 19, pp. 417-439.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 2, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Ford, Paul Leicester, 1865-1902
    Brooklyn, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns Jefferson letters in A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 3, 1899; 9x6; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Introduces G.G. MacCurdy.
  - Letter to E[lla M] Morrison [sic, Morison], Jan. 3, 1899; 9-1/2x6; Reade manufacturing company
    New York, A.L.S.: W. J. Reade 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends payment for Proceedings, no.157.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 5, 1899; 9-1/2x6; Ingham, William A. (William Armstrong), 1827-1913
    Phila., Concerns mail for A.P.S. Secretaries.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 6, 1899; 7x4-1/2 8-1/2x4; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 4p. Enc. of 1p. printed ballot, end. Sends marked ballot for annual election. Eulogizes William Pepper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 6, 1899; 9x6; Howe, Robert
    Orlando, Fla., A.L.S. 1p. Orders copy of F.H. Cushing's "Exploration of ancient Key dwellers."
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 7, 1899; 9x6; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Encs. wanting Returns all proofs in his possession, and key to Secretaries' closet.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 8, 1899; 7x4-1/2, 8x5; MacCurdy, George Grant, 1863-1947
    New Haven [Conn.] A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Gives address of Duc de Loubat. Enclosure of Hays's memorandum on the Duc.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 8, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Matthews, Fla., A.L.S. 2p. Will serve as Curator if elected.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 9, 1899; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment as Curator.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Jan. 9, 1899; 3-1/2X5-1/2; Marshall, John, 1855-1925
    Phila., A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 9, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Has received notice of election as Vice-president.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 10, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Barker, George F. (George Frederick), 1835-1910
    [Phila.] A.L. on postal card S. 1p., and add. Concerns meeting (of Vice-presidents?) Refers to C. Sellers.
  - Letters to the American philosophical society, Jan.12 - Dec. 6, 1899; 10x8; Library Bureau
    6 typed L. 6p. Acknowledgements of library supply orders.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hayes [sic, Hays], Jan. 13, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Sadtler, Samuel P. (Samuel Philip), 1847-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts post of Secretary.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Jan. 13, 1899; 10x 8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington [D.C.] Typed L.S.: Alvey A[ugustus] Adee 1p. Concerns A.P.S. exchanges with Mexican government.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays, Jan. 31, 1899?; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S. 1p. and add. Aaks if G.W. Myers's paper was presented at last meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Campbell, Irving E.
    Richmond, Va., Typed L. with MS. corrections S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize. On same sheet is draft of reply from W[illia]m V[incent] McKean to Campbell, [1899]
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 14, 1899; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Los Angeles Public Library
    Los Angeles, Calif., Typed L.S.: H[arriet] C[hild] Wadleigh 1p. Enc. want. Sends payment for copies of Transactions.
  - Letter to J [sic, Isaac] Minis Hays, Jan. 14, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Converse, John H. (John Heman), 1840-1910
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends nomination of S.M. Vauclain. Refers to C. Sellers.
  - Letters to Isaac Minis Hays, Jan.16 - Dec. 13, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Penrose, Boies, 1860-1921
    Washington and Philadelphia, 13 Typed L.S. 13p. Concern various unnamed documents being sent to A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l [Phillip] Sadtler, Jan. 18, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    West Chester, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Michaux Legacy Committee.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 20, 1899; 8x5-1/2; Cushing, Frank Hamilton, 1857-1900
    Washington, D.C., A.L.S. 7p. Inquires about William Bartram manuscript once in possession of S.G. Morton, and J.H. Payne manuscript on Cherokees. Refers to E.G. Squier.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Jan. 20, 1899; 7x5-1/2; Himes, Martha L.
    Phila., [?] A.L.S. 2p. Offers to exchange old volumes of A.P.S. Transactions for copies of Isaac Lea's papers on shells.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 23, 1899; 9x6; Appleton, William Hyde, 1838?-1926
    Swarthmore, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for issues of Proceedings which he lacks.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 24, 1899; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.] L.S. 2p. Appoints Standing Committees on Finance, Hall, Publications and Library.
  - Letter to [James Ludovic, 26th] Earl of Crawford, Jan. 25, 1899; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Carbon copy with MS. corrections 4p. Lists A.P.S. holdings of journals kept by his ancestor, John Lindsay, 20th Earl of Crawford.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, Jan. 25, 1899; 10-1/2x8; United States. Navy Dept.
    Washington, Typed L.S.: John D[avis] Long 1p. Concerns copy of "Battles and capitulation of Santiago de Cuba" for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to A.P.S., Jan. 30, 1899.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morison, Jan. 26, 1899; 9x6; Jayne, Horace, 1859-1913
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Concerns dues of W.H. Appleton, A.J. Cassatt, F. Morley.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Prime, Jan. 26, 1899; 11x8-1/2; MacCalla and co., inc.
    Phila., Typed L.S.: W[illiam] A. Pickell 1p. Concerns proofs for Pepper Memorial article. Refers to I.M. Hays. For printed memorial, see: APS Memorial Vol. 1.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 26, 1899; 8x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Library Committee.
  - Letter to Boies Penrose, Jan. 26, 1899; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Treasury
    Washington, Typed L.S.: L[yman] J[udson] Gage 1p., end. Concerns copy of "Lights and for-signals on the Atlantic and Gulf coasts" requested for A.P.S. library. With covering letter from Penrose to A.P.S., Jan. 30, 1899.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 27, 1899; 11x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Phila., Typed L.S. with stamp. 1p. Asks for list of A.P.S. officers.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 28, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Buti, Rudolph
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends his statement on fragment of the "Book of the dead." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 38, pp. 79-81.
  - Letter to S[amuel] P[hillip] Sadtler, Jan. 28, 1899; 10-1/2x8; Dickson, Samuel, 1837-1915
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Declines to serve on Hall Committee and Magellanic Premium trust.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 28, 1899; 6-1/2x8-1/2; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Accepts appointment to Committee on Publication.
  - Letter to Joseph G[eorge] Rosengarten, Jan. 29, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Pennypacker, Samuel W. (Samuel Whitaker), 1843-1916
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Will write preface to George Weedon's Valley Forge Orderly Book. On verso is J.G. Rosengarten to I.M. Hays, Jan.31, 1899.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Jan. 30, 1899; 11x8; Maryland Historical Society
    Baltimore, Typed L.S.: Mendes Cohen 1p. Concerns A.P.S. set of Maryland Archives.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 31, 1899; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Cleemann, Richard A. (Richard Alsop), 1840-1912
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns A.P.S. Minute Books.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 31, 1899; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Jefferis, William W., 1820-1906
    New York, A.L. on postal card S. 1p. and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Jan. 31, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns S.W. Pennypacker's preface to Valley Forge Orderly Book. Written on verso of Pennypacker to Rosengarten, Jan. 29, 1899.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Feb. 1, 1899; 7x4-1/2; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 4p. When did A.P.S. acquire William Temple Franklin collection of Franklin material? Refers to Franklin Bache, William Duane.